<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: updates | The PressGang CCMS Project]]></title>
  <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/categories/updates/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-26T13:33:28+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The PressGang CCMS Project]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bugfixes]]></title>
    <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/Bugfixes/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T12:04:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/Bugfixes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I applied a minor bug fix release last night to the PressGang servers. Fixes are as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed the Double Login Issue. See Bug #867507</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the Topic XML Editor wouldn't display when switching tabs.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with pushing Translations to Zanata.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Converstions weren't being ended when an error was thrown.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where entering an invalid topic Id in the Quick Select box would just cause the page to reload. It now will display the  Angry Terminator.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the REST Server would throw an NPE when expanding LogDetails.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the Project Description Query parameter wouldn't work.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes to Translation Workflow]]></title>
    <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/change-to-translation-workflow/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-12T13:06:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/change-to-translation-workflow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The short version.</p>

<p>With the release of Zanata 2.0 it is now no longer necessary to run copytrans when pushing topics to Zanata. Topics will reuse the translations from previous revisions (if available) automatically. It is still good practice to notify translators of new topic revisions, but there is no longer any need to request copytrans be run.</p>

<!-- MORE -->


<p>The long version.</p>

<p>Prior to Zanata 2.0 only Zanata documents (topics are considered documents by Zanata) that were in the same project and that had the same file name would reuse translations from the older versions of the documents. Since CCMS topics in Zanata are identified by a revision number, each revision had a different file name, and this meant that there was no automatic reuse of prior translations. The only way around this was to manually run copytrans, which would prepopulate translations for all documents in a project. Hence the previous requirement to request that copytrans be run when new topics were pushed into Zanata.</p>

<p>Zanata 2.0 now has the ability to reuse translations according to a flexible set of rules, which now allows CCMS topics to be prepopulated with existing translations when they are pushed into the system. There is nothing that writers or translators need to do take advantage of this new feature; it is implemented as a standard part of the process when pushing topics into Zanata.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in Skynet #23]]></title>
    <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2011/11/23/this-week-in-skynet-no22/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-23T15:33:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2011/11/23/this-week-in-skynet-no22</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week we upgraded to using HTTPS on the server and continued to extend the Zanata support.</p>

<!-- MORE -->


<h3>HTTPS Login</h3>

<p>The login page now uses HTTPS. The certificate is not signed, so you will have to add the certificate in Firefox, or ignore the security warning in Chrome.</p>

<h3>Continued Work on Zanata Integration</h3>

<p>Work has continued on providing integration with Zanata. After a meeting with the Zanata guys I have had to expand Skynet's role to address the following decisions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Skynet will be responsible for maintaining the state of a translation at a point in time (equivalent to downloading a PO file and checking it into an SVN repo)</li>
<li>Skynet will provide the interface used by translators to view, sort and compare topics that have been translated</li>
<li>Zanata will provide a fixed URL for editing a specific topic, which will appear in Skynet to allow translators to do the actual translations.</li>
</ul>


<p>Snapshots can now only be created from the main search screen. The tags and topic field filters are selected (as if you were going to build a DocBook ZIP file) and then a Snapshot is created, essentially freezing the state of the topics returned by the search fields.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/Screenshot-at-2011-11-29-17-46-42.png"><img src="/images/uploads/Screenshot-at-2011-11-29-17-46-42.png" title="Creating new snapshots from search" ></a></p>

<p>Once created, Snapshots can be queried from their own search page.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/Screenshot-at-2011-11-29-17-47-09.png"><img src="/images/uploads/Screenshot-at-2011-11-29-17-47-09.png" title="Snapshots can be queried from their own search page" ></a></p>

<p>The snapshot topics (either belonging to a specific revision, or just in the working state) can be queried just like regular topics, complete with grouping. In future it is likely that there will be a number of tags to represent translation priorities, which translators can use to organise their workflow.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/Screenshot-at-2011-11-29-17-40-56.png"><img src="/images/uploads/Screenshot-at-2011-11-29-17-40-56.png" title="Zanata IDs in Tags" ></a></p>

<p>Snapshots now have the concept of a revision. A revision is kind of like a snapshot for a snapshot. When created, a revision will save the translation strings and the translated XML, allowing books to be recreated at a later point with a known translation set. When a snapshot is first created, an initial revision named "Initial Untranslated Revision" is created that reflects the untranslated state of the topics.</p>

<p>In addition to revisions, translations can be pulled down into a working state. The working state represents the topics translated against the latest strings in Zanata. This gives translators the ability to view and compare translated documents without having to create a snapshot revision.</p>

<p>There is still more work to be done, but I am hoping that I can get a working example uploaded by the end of the week, or maybe early next week.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in Skynet #22]]></title>
    <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2011/11/21/this-week-in-skynet-no23/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-21T08:33:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2011/11/21/this-week-in-skynet-no23</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week has been all about integrating Skynet with Zanata.</p>

<!-- MORE -->


<h3>Integration with Zanata</h3>

<p>First, the concept of a Snapshot has been added to Skynet. A Snapshot captures the state of a collection of topics that are returned by a filtered search. It is intended to be used to save significant milestones or releases, such as beta releases or GA releases.</p>

<p>To create a snapshot you first select the tags and field filter options that would return the topics that represent a significant release. You then select the Snapshots tab, enter a new for the new Snapshot, and click Save.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Once a Snapshot has been created, it can not be modified or deleted. So make sure that all the topics are OK before creating a Snapshot, because if any topics have invalid XML they can not be translated or included in the Docbook output, and the XML can not be changed.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/skynet1.png"><img src="/images/uploads/skynet1.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>When the Snapshot has been created, you can push the Topics to Zanata using the Push All To Zanata button. Zanata does not understand the concept of a Topic, so as a work around a Zanata project called Skynet is created, and each revision of a topic is uploaded as a separate file.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/skynet2.png"><img src="/images/uploads/skynet2.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/skynet3.png"><img src="/images/uploads/skynet3.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>When a translation has been completed, click the Pull All From Zanata button. This will pull down the translated strings, and apply them to the Snapshot topics.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/skynet4.png"><img src="/images/uploads/skynet4.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>The translated version of the topics can then be previewed using the View Topic button.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/skynet5.png"><img src="/images/uploads/skynet5.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>There is still a lot lot be done (including dealing with injection points, building a Docbook ZIP file from a Snapshot, prioritising topics for translation to name a few), but as a proof of concept this work paves the way for further integration between Skynet and Zanata.</p>

<p>For the technically inclined, the <a href="https://sourceforge.net/p/topicindex/code/425/tree/trunk/WebContent/WEB-INF/lib/zanatarest.jar">zanatarest.jar</a> file contains the Java classes required to use the Zanata REST interface directly via a <a href="http://docs.jboss.org/resteasy/2.0.0.GA/userguide/html/RESTEasy_Client_Framework.html#Sharing_interfaces">RESTeasy client</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Weekend in Skynet]]></title>
    <link href="http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2011/11/13/this-weekend-in-skynet/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-13T08:39:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://pressgang-ccms.github.com/blog/2011/11/13/this-weekend-in-skynet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A busy weekend has added grouping to search results.</p>

<!-- MORE -->


<h3>Grouped Topic Searches</h3>

<p>Search results can now be grouped. The main search screen has a new column next to the tags labelled Grp. Any tag with the Grp (or grouping) checkbox selected will be used to group the search result.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/untitled.png"><img src="/images/uploads/untitled.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>On the search screen each grouping tag is represented by a tab. These tabs list all the topics that match the filter AND include the grouping tag. This means that a topic might be listed more than once under different tabs.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/2.png"><img src="/images/uploads/2.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>Topics that don't include any of the grouping tags will be listed under a tab called Ungrouped Results. This means that, when using grouping, all topics that would have been returned by the filter are listed at least once under once of the tabs, and possibly more than once.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/3.png"><img src="/images/uploads/3.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>

<p>All group operations, such as bulk tagging or group relationship modifications, are performed on all the topics, and not just those in the currently selected tab.</p>

<h3>Exception Logging</h3>

<p>All exceptions are now logged to the database. This should allow me to monitor occurrences of the angry terminator, and hopefully resolve these kinds of issues in a more timely fashion.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/4.png"><img src="/images/uploads/4.png" title="untitled" ></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
